# **BETHANY GROGG**

South Berwick, ME 03908

Phone: 207-384-4156 | Email: Bethany.Grogg@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bethany-grogg-809093b0/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/bethany-grogg-809093b0/</a> | Github: <a href="https://github.com/BethGrogg">https://github.com/BethGrogg</a>

Portfolio: <a href="https://bethgrogg.github.io/Portfolio/">https://bethgrogg.github.io/Portfolio/</a>

#### **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Developer with a background in HTML, CSS, Javascript and JQuery programming. Previous experience with Java and COBOL. Problem solver with an interest in learning new technologies. Values effective communication and collaboration. Productive contributor working both alone and as part of a team. Graduate of the University of New Hampshire's Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp program.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize, Semantic UI, Firebase, AJAX, JSON, MySQL, Handlebars, Express, Node.js

#### **PROJECTS**

**2020 Election** | <a href="https://github.com/rcreveling/project-one">https://github.com/rcreveling/project-one</a> | <a href="https://creveling.github.io/project-one/">https://creveling.github.io/project-one/</a>

- An application for up-to-date, unbiased information about the 2020 elections.
- Developed the slider at the top of the page of relevant articles and the overall design of the application.
- Created with HTML, CSS, Materialize, Javascript, JQuery, Propublica APIs, New York Times API, canvas.js

**Trivia Game** | https://github.com/BethGrogg/TriviaGame | https://bethgrogg.github.io/TriviaGame/

- A "Friends" trivia game based on the television show.
- Created with HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery.

Train Scheduler | https://github.com/BethGrogg/Train Scheduler | https://bethgrogg.github.io/Train Scheduler/

- An application that simulates train schedules and updating their information based on the current time.
- Created with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, JQuery, moment.js.

#### EXPERIENCE

# **Special Education Educational Technician RSU 35**

2015-2019 Eliot, ME

- One-to-one support for students. Provided a safe, confidential environment, adhering to Individualized Educational Program plans. Role required problem-solving skills and effective communication.
- Suggested a bus drop off plan that was successfully implemented, decreasing transitions for our students.

Software Engineer Liberty Mutual Insurance 2000-2005 Portsmouth, NH

Two years BFT program, 3 years in Commercial Markets, mostly Java.

**Information Systems Specialist Travelers Insurance Company** 

1997-2000 Hartford, CT

#### **E**DUCATION

### **Bootcamp Certification: University of New Hampshire**

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

# **Business-Focused Training (BFT): Liberty Mutual Insurance**

A 2 year program designed to educate software engineers on different aspects of the business through internships with the program, culminating in a year long technical project.

Bachelor of Science in Dietetics: James Madison University, Harrisonburg, VA